virtualhelper247.com 2015-12-06

# Privacy

Hire A Virtual Assistant Today

**Virtual Helper 247 respects your privacy.**

Virtual Helper 247 recognises the importance of compliance with Australian Privacy Laws particularly with respect to personal information. For this reason Virtual Helper 247 has adopted a privacy of information policy consistent with Australian Privacy Legislation and the ten National Principles for the Fair Handling of Personal Information.

The following privacy statement applies to all business conducted by Virtual Helper 247 within the IT industry, be it through any of its offices or over any of its websites. This statement covers all personal information collected by Virtual Helper 247 during the conduct of any of its authorised Sales, Services, Human Resources or Recruitment procedures.

Virtual Helper 247 endeavours to protect all collected personal information from unauthorised use or disclosure.

**Collection**

Virtual Helper 247 endeavours to collect any personal information directly from the individual with that individuals consent. Where personal information is provided to Virtual Helper 247 by third parties, relevant staff will always take reasonable steps to obtain consent from the individual to whom the information pertains where required by the legislation. Virtual Helper 247 only collects personal information that is necessary for the conduct of its business, be it by the company internal, Sales, Services or Recruitment divisions. Without the provision of the requested information by the individual, Virtual Helper 247 is unable to effectively complete the relevant business activity. Within Virtual Helper 247 Sales and Services divisions, personal information is only disclosed to suppliers and customers relevant to the particular business that the individual is conducting with Virtual Helper 247. Within Virtual Helper 247 Recruitment division personal information is collected relating only to the practise of recruitment and assessment of candidates. Such information may be provided to prospective employers and employees in a range of industries requiring information technology skills or services. Any Virtual Helper 247 client, customer, business partner or recruitment candidate who does not wish their personal information to be provided to any particular organisation or types of organisations should notify Virtual Helper 247 at the time of the collection of the personal information.

**Use and Disclosure**

As a major provider of a range of information technology products, services and resource solutions, Virtual Helper 247 primary purpose for collecting personal information is to facilitate the efficient provision of quality information technology products and services to its business associates. Apart from the completion of the original business dealing this may involve the provision of relevant product and industry updates and other market related information and opportunities to Virtual Helper 247 business associates. Should you prefer not to receive any such information please advise Virtual Helper 247 by contacting the our Privacy Officer as detailed above.

**Data Quality**

Virtual Helper 247 continuously monitors the accuracy of personal information on collection from and provision by the individual and through the day-to-day processes of its business. Should any updates to your personal information be required please contact and inform Virtual Helper 247.

**Data Security**

As an information technology company, Virtual Helper 247 employs state of the art security systems and procedures to ensure the integrity and security of personal information held by the company. Personal information does not leave Virtual Helper 247 internal systems unless required to effect the primary purpose of your business with Virtual Helper 247, or unless consented to. Should personal information be required to be removed from our offices for business purposes, increased security measures are employed. Despite the high level of information security employed within Virtual Helper 247 and its commitment to your privacy, the company is unable to provide an absolute assurance that personal information will remain secure at all times. Virtual Helper 247 therefore does not accept any responsibility for incidences of unauthorised access to personal information, which is provided at your own risk. Likewise Virtual Helper 247 does not guarantee the security or privacy compliance of any websites that are accessible through links provided on any of its websites. Virtual Helper 247 will delete from its systems any of your personal information held by the company on your request provided that sufficient proof of identity is established.

**Openness**

Virtual Helper 247 Privacy Statement is available on its websites or internally on its intranet. Personal information held by Virtual Helper 247 is limited to that which is required for the legitimate functions of the company business. Any queries regarding position on privacy should be directed to Virtual Helper 247 privacy officer via e-mail to info@virtualhelper247.com

**Access and Correction**

Virtual Helper 247 undertakes to provide access to individuals to any of their personal information held by the company for the purpose of review and correction with exception to the limitations imposed by the privacy legislation. Requests for access should be forwarded to Virtual Helper 247 privacy officer along with sufficient proof of identification.

**Identifiers**

Virtual Helper 247 limits the use of government identifiers to the purposes required of the company by legislation only.

**Anonymity**

My Virtual Assistant’s personnel will respect a request for anonymity unless and until relevant business negotiations are entered into. None of Virtual Helper 247 business processes can be completed effectively with either party remaining anonymous.

**Transborder Data Flows**

Although Virtual Helper 247 is a national company the company does occasionally engage in international business. In these instances we undertake not to send or disclose personal information without the consent of the individual. In any event Virtual Helper 247 takes precautions to ensure that any of its business partners employ similar policies documenting the recognition of their privacy obligations.

**Sensitive Information**

Virtual Helper 247 does not require that you supply any sensitive information to the company unless it is essential for the purpose of the conduct of business. This type of information will not be collected without your consent.
